In this course, we have established that the
BETWEEN keyword is used to set criteria to
return records between two numbers or two dates.
Sometimes, though, we just want to see something
greater than or less than a number or something
that occurs before or after a certain date. Take,
for example, this query that shows orders placed
in a certain month. What if I just want to see
orders that happened after a certain date. I will
change the WHERE clause to use a greater than
symbol (>), one of several comparison operators,
to show orders that occurred after June 1, 2014.
I will execute this, and we get
just over 900 rows. One real-life
aspect of comparisons to consider is this: If
someone says, get me everything after June 1,
does the person really mean that? Or, should June
1 be included? Sometimes, you will need to clarify
those situations. Right now, our results
do not show anything on June 1 because we
indicated we wanted to see activity from after
that date. However, if I change the comparison
operator to greater than or equal to (>=) and then
execute this again, we get the orders from June 1.
Let's use the SubTotal field to see the less than
(<) and less than or equal to (<=) comparisons at
work. I will add AND Subtotal < 159 to this
criteria. We do not need single quotes around
this amount because this is a numeric value. I
will execute this query, and we do lose a few
records. Let's see what happens when I change
the criteria to <= and execute this again.
We see three more records as three orders have a
subtotal of exactly 159 dollars. The big takeaway
with comparison operators isn't how to use
these operators; it is making sure we understand
exactly what someone wants in situations
in which comparison operators can be used.